### Contact

Kolkata, India 00919831023987 (Home) sudipto.im@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sudipto-basak (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**Databases** 

Linux

Performance Tuning

#### Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

AWS Certified Developer - Associate
AWS Certified Big Data Specialty

# Sudipto Basak

Oracle/AWS Architect

Parsippany, New Jersey

## Summary

Experienced data architect and Oracle expert, Extensive experience in Oracle, Data warehousing and BI, Big Data ecosystem, Certified AWS Solutions Architect, Developer and Big Data Specialist. Have working knowledge on Java, Python, Spring Boot microservice framework, Docker, Swarm and Kubernetes.

## Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions
Data Architect - Wyndham Exchange & Rentals
January 2013 - Present
Parsippany, NJ

Data Architecture, Data Modeling standards/guidelines and DW solutioning for Wyndham Exchange & Rentals. Consulting on Oracle Database technical issues, ETL processing.

Cognizant Technology Soutions Oracle Database Architect November 2010 - Present Kolkata, India

As part of Data Architecture Consulting group (DAC) in Cognizant, my primary responsibilities are consulting on database technical issues, database architecture and design, non-functional analysis, large scale data movement/migration.

Tata Consultancy Servcies
Oracle Database Architect - British Telecommunication Plc.
March 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 8 months)
Kolkata, India; Cardiff, UK

Managing over a 50TB system with responsibility:

Database Architecture Design and Administration

Capacity Planning and Maintenance

Infrastructure Design and Build (including Backup/Recovery)

Unix/Linux Administration

Performance Tuning (Oracle and Unix)

Tata Consultancy Services
Application Support Lead - BT Wholesale
November 2005 - March 2008 (2 years 5 months)
Application Support and Maintenance
Live Environment Support
Live Database Support

### Education

Jadavpur University
BE, Production Engineering · (2001 - 2005)